Thing online about possible changes proposed by nominees for president elect Trump's cabinet
One of those changes will be to tap water
Sheryl Mercedes explains why the proposal is already causing some backlash
Why has the nomination of Robert Kennedy Jr as the head of health and Human Services sparked a new debate about fluoride in drinking water
RFK Jr has said he will advise local water systems to remove fluoride from public drinking water?
According to the centers for Disease Control close to 63 percent of Americans have a fluoridated water coming out of their taps.
Local municipalities make the decision whether or not to add fluoride to the water supply.
The US Environmental Protection Agency only mandates a limit on how much can be put in.
So what is fluoride? It is a naturally occurring mineral that is already found in some water supplies.
That's actually how we discovered it helped teeth
Dentists noticed that people living in areas with fluoride in the water had less tooth decay and better enamel.
In 1945, Grand Rapids, Michigan became the first city in the world to add fluoride to its water supply
Research shows the rate of cavities and children there decreased by more than 60 percent.
The debate over fluoride stems from what happens when there is too much in the water
A recent scientific paper found a possible link between high fluoride levels and lower IQs in children
but those fluoride levels were double what is recommended by the ETA.
Exports say more research is needed and warned that facts, not conspiracy theories should inform that debate.
with the Y I'm Sheryl Mercedes